Guide to the Boniface I. Obichere papers, 1959-1996
Obichere, Boniface I. papers, 1959-1996
- Series X. Audio and Visual Materials
  - Photographs, Slides, and Postcards
    - Postcards: Trinidad and Tobago (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Audio and Video Recordings
    - Cassette tapes: Clarke, Dr. John Henrik, interview(?), n.d. (Box 33)
    - Cassette tapes: Drake, Dr. St. Clair, oral interview and background information (4 tapes) (Box 33)
    - Cassette tapes: Lee, Dr., interview(?), n.d. (Box 33)
    - Cassette tapes: Malcolm X., "The Ballot or the Bullet", n.d. (Box 33)
    - Cassette tapes: Malcolm X., "The Last Message", n.d. (Box 33)
    - Cassette tapes: Malcolm X., "Message to the Grass Roots", n.d. (Box 33)
    - Cassette tapes: Malcolm X., "Oxford Debates", n.d. (Box 33)
    - Cassette tapes: Malcolm X., "Speeches in Harlem" (2 tapes), n.d. (Box 33)
    - Cassette tapes: Pabi, Inez, interview(?), n.d. (Box 33)
    - 3" reel-to-reel tapes: National University of S.A. students, Sept. 15, 1971 (Box 34)
    - 3" reel-to-reel tapes: Interview of Tidiare Sy (2 tapes), Feb. 24, 1972 (Box 34)
    - 3" reel-to-reel tapes: Sat Conference, Liberation movements (2 tapes), Nov. 4, 1972 (Box 34)
    - 3" reel-to-reel tapes: Nkrumah at Lincoln, Richard Wright in Ghana, n.d. (Box 34)
    - 3" reel-to-reel tapes: Panel Ethiopa (no box), n.d. (Box 34)
    - 3" reel-to-reel tapes: (2) Unidentified, no boxes, n.d. (Box 34)
    - 4" reel-to-reel tapes: Interviews with Omanhenes, Central and Western Ghana, Mar. 8-12, 1971 (Box 34)
    - 4" reel-to-reel tapes: Ashanti (Manpongteng), Hierarchy of Ashanti states, Slavery in Ashanti Kingdom and Empire, Mar. 18, 1971 (Box 34)
    - 5" reel-to-reel tapes: Tribute to Cabral, African Activist Association, Jan. 25, 1973 (Box 34)
    - 5" reel-to-reel tapes: Unlabeled, no box, n.d. (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: African Studies Center, UCLA, Rm 10244 Social Sciences, Carol J. McLaurin, for BBC, Nov. 17, 1967 (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: Mafoha to edit, Feb. 2, 1972 (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: Cultural Relations and Exchanges between South African and the U.S. (2 tapes, plus dups), Nov. 9, 1972 (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: Economic Relations Between South African and the U.S. (2 tapes), Nov. 9, 1972 (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: Liberation in Southern Africa (2 tapes), Nov. 9, 1972 (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: U.S. Congress and South Africa, ASA Committee on Current Issues, Nov. 10, 1972 (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: Conference on Guerilla Movement, May 3, 1973 (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: Stella Makunja, UNITA, May 17, 1973 (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: Ruth's first speech, "Southern Africa Liberation Movements", Apr. 17, 1974 (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: Conversation on Pan-Africanism, n.d. (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: Gil Fernandez - Guinea Bisseau Liberation Movements (Box 34)
    - 7" reel-to-reel tapes: Dr. D.I. Nwoga, University of Nigeria, on African literature, n.d. (Box 34)
    - Filmstrip: "Is it Safe to Eat Anything Anymore?", 1979 (Box 34)
    - VHS: "Julius Nyerere: Reflections of an Elder Statesman," produced by Melvin McCray and Jan Robinson, 1988 (Box 34)
    - Records: "Buffalo Soldier" by Bob Marley and the Wailers, 1983 (Box 34)
    - Records: Radio Canada International, 1976 (Box 34)
  - Textile objects
    - (4) wall hangings, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Egyptian wall hanging, n.d. (Folder 4)
    - Bandana (Box 35)
    - South African flag, n.d. (Box 35)
  - Ephemera
    - Poster: "Times of Zambia", 1971 (Folder 1)
    - Poster: "Adinkra Symbolism", 1971 (Box 36)
    - Poster: (2) of African men, 1 is a xerox, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Fisk Jubilee Singers program, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Menu, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Ethiopan Airlines ticket holder, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Ghana Airways timetable, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Xerox image of an African man, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - "Senegalese Images", 1983 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Puzzle of Africa, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - English, French, Nigerian money, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous keys, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Buttons, n.d. (Box 33)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
This collection included a large number of books used by Boniface Obichere relating to Africa and African history. These volumes have been separated and will be made available at the John Henrik Clarke Africana Library at Cornell University.